Jack Burkhardt

Chicago, Illinois, United States | mail@jackburkhardt.com | (312)-478-9592 | https://jackburkhardt.com

Summary

I'm a freshman at Northwestern University studying the intersection between Computer Science and Philosophy. I enjoy studying the philosophical and real world implications of a maturing internet and designing story-based games that evoke emotion and fully utilize the power of games as an art form. My goal is to design things that makes the lives of others happier and more just.

I have a strong background in computers and servers, in both software and hardware, and experience ranging from setup to maintenance to troubleshooting. I also have a lot of experience in event hosting and project management for various computer science nonprofits across Chicago.

Experience



Special Services Associate

The Home Depot

May 2020 - Present (10 months +)

- Generated \$10,000+ in sales for my store while reducing order pick times and increasing pick accuracy, and received Homer awards for doing so
- Worked with HD's electronic systems to manage customer orders, information, and store inventory- Handled customer service, sales, returns, delivery scheduling, and order picking, often doing multiple duties simultaneously



Freelance System Administration

Freelance, self-employed

Sep 2017 - Present (3 years 6 months +)

Purchased and set up several dedicated servers for hobby use and hosting

- Hosted and/or developed for over 30 different gameservers
- Created and maintained multiple personal, business, and community websites with software including Wordpress, Mediawiki, and LAMP
- Used tools such as Docker and bash scripting to enhance workflow



Volunteer

FREEGEEK CHICAGO NFP

Sep 2018 - Mar 2020 (1 year 7 months)

- Tore down donated technology and responsibly recycled materials
- Tested salvaged parts for reusability, reducing e-waste produced
- Constructed new computers using recycled parts and sold at a low price, making computers more accessible



Student Mentor at CodeDay Chicago

CodeDay

Nov 2019 - Dec 2020 (1 year 2 months)

- Worked with other mentors and venue staff to make sure events ran smoothly, and on schedule but was a fun and educational experience for attendees
- Advised teams during both proposal and development phases, encouraging them to expose themselves to new technologies and strategies



Event Coordinator

Chicode

Dec 2018 - Jun 2020 (1 year 7 months)

- Founded and organized the annual Jones Jam 12 hour hackathon, hosting over 80 attendees and 15 volunteers
- Managed planning, logistics, and training for activities and workshops while preparing event volunteers and speakers
- Led fundraising and advertising campaigns that stretched across the Chicago Public Schools system

Education



Northwestern University

Bachelor of Arts - BA, Computer Science

- Current Technology Chair for Shepard Residential College
- Education Team member of the Responsible Al Student Org



Solution Jones College Prep

High School Diploma 2016 - 2020

- Enrolled in all Honors level or Advanced Placement classes
- Founder and leader of both the school Robotics club/team and Computer Science club
- Recipient of Jones Computer Science Award
- Jones College Prep High Honor Roll (2016-2020)